<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/DNA-replication-group-website/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/DNA-replication-group-website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-10-30T09:55:50+00:00</updated><id>/DNA-replication-group-website/feed.xml</id><title type="html">DNA Replication Group</title><subtitle>Exploring the impact of DNA replication on genome evolution and stability.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Functional Multi-Omics Symposium 2025</title><link href="/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/10/17/multi-omics.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Functional Multi-Omics Symposium 2025" /><published>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/10/17/multi-omics</id><content type="html" xml:base="/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/10/17/multi-omics.html"><![CDATA[<!-- excerpt start -->
<p>The latest multi-omics approaches to study biological systems.
<!-- excerpt end -->
I went to the inaugural Functional Multi-Omics Conference hosted by the new Centre of Microbial Interactions (CMI) here on the Norwich Research Park. CMI’s aim is to bring together all those individuals who work on microbes on the park to improve collaboration, communication and innovation. The day revolved around genomics, proteomics, metabolomics, and transcriptomics, with a focus on how to integrate data across the different approaches. They hosed keynote speaker Professor Lars Barquist, open panel discussion around the integration of functional multi-omics data and several flash talks and posters. I found the conference enjoyable – they even had interactive group sessions! One of which used multi-omics approaches to figure out which pathway was producing a metabolite of interest. As someone who isn’t much involved in multi-omic approaches I felt like I learned a lot including how powerful multi-omic approaches can be for scientific discovery and potentially how it could align to my own work or future horizons as a PhD student.</p>]]></content><author><name>CC</name></author><category term="Science" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest multi-omics approaches to study biological systems. I went to the inaugural Functional Multi-Omics Conference hosted by the new Centre of Microbial Interactions (CMI) here on the Norwich Research Park. CMI’s aim is to bring together all those individuals who work on microbes on the park to improve collaboration, communication and innovation. The day revolved around genomics, proteomics, metabolomics, and transcriptomics, with a focus on how to integrate data across the different approaches. They hosed keynote speaker Professor Lars Barquist, open panel discussion around the integration of functional multi-omics data and several flash talks and posters. I found the conference enjoyable – they even had interactive group sessions! One of which used multi-omics approaches to figure out which pathway was producing a metabolite of interest. As someone who isn’t much involved in multi-omic approaches I felt like I learned a lot including how powerful multi-omic approaches can be for scientific discovery and potentially how it could align to my own work or future horizons as a PhD student.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Earlham Institute Innovate event 2025</title><link href="/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/10/15/EI-Innovate.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Earlham Institute Innovate event 2025" /><published>2025-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/10/15/EI-Innovate</id><content type="html" xml:base="/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/10/15/EI-Innovate.html"><![CDATA[<!-- excerpt start -->
<p>EI Innovate is our institute’s annual engagement event that provides insight into our research, exploring opportunities for innovation and collaboration.
<!-- excerpt end -->
I attended and presented a poster at the annual EI Innovate Conference in October 2025. The day aims to foster collaboration, share success stories with the latest technologies and advancements and build networks to enable partnerships in future. The day started off with talks from PhD students (chaired by Conrad) whose projects are shared with an industry partner, detailing the benefits of a PhD in collaboration and how it developed their early career. There were also many talk from fantastic researchers including Dr. Philip Zegerman from Tropic Bioscience and their new product the anti-browning banana, and Professor Tom Ellis (Imperial) with his synthetic genome modules work. After the lunch I presented my poster detailing my project <em>The Causes and Consequences of Short Tandem Repeats on the Human Genome</em> and how the use of ONT Nanopore Flow Cells is enabling my research. I enjoyed explaining the science and the challenge of communicating it to a varied audience – some of whom were based in business/law and had no scientific background. Overall the day the was very interesting and something I would recommend others to participate in if offered the chance.</p>]]></content><author><name>CC</name></author><category term="Science" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[EI Innovate is our institute’s annual engagement event that provides insight into our research, exploring opportunities for innovation and collaboration. I attended and presented a poster at the annual EI Innovate Conference in October 2025. The day aims to foster collaboration, share success stories with the latest technologies and advancements and build networks to enable partnerships in future. The day started off with talks from PhD students (chaired by Conrad) whose projects are shared with an industry partner, detailing the benefits of a PhD in collaboration and how it developed their early career. There were also many talk from fantastic researchers including Dr. Philip Zegerman from Tropic Bioscience and their new product the anti-browning banana, and Professor Tom Ellis (Imperial) with his synthetic genome modules work. After the lunch I presented my poster detailing my project The Causes and Consequences of Short Tandem Repeats on the Human Genome and how the use of ONT Nanopore Flow Cells is enabling my research. I enjoyed explaining the science and the challenge of communicating it to a varied audience – some of whom were based in business/law and had no scientific background. Overall the day the was very interesting and something I would recommend others to participate in if offered the chance.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome Warren</title><link href="/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/10/10/Warren-visit.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome Warren" /><published>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/10/10/Warren-visit</id><content type="html" xml:base="/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/10/10/Warren-visit.html"><![CDATA[<!-- excerpt start -->
<p>Welcome to Warren (Cai group, Manchester) - visiting for three months.
<!-- excerpt end --></p>]]></content><author><name>conrad</name></author><category term="Science" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to Warren (Cai group, Manchester) - visiting for three months.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tubing &amp;amp; Isabel’s last day</title><link href="/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/09/25/Tubing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tubing &amp;amp; Isabel’s last day" /><published>2025-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/09/25/Tubing</id><content type="html" xml:base="/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/09/25/Tubing.html"><![CDATA[<!-- excerpt start -->
<p>Celebrating all of Isabel’s contributions with tubing and dinner, then cake on her last day.
<!-- excerpt end --></p>]]></content><author><name>DC</name></author><category term="Group social" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Celebrating all of Isabel’s contributions with tubing and dinner, then cake on her last day.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Birmingham Genome Biology Conference</title><link href="/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/09/11/Birmingham-conference.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Birmingham Genome Biology Conference" /><published>2025-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-09-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/09/11/Birmingham-conference</id><content type="html" xml:base="/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/09/11/Birmingham-conference.html"><![CDATA[<!-- excerpt start -->
<p>Eduardo and Isabel presented at the Birmingham Centre for Genome Biology 2025 Conference.
<!-- excerpt end --></p>]]></content><author><name>EV</name></author><category term="Science" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Eduardo and Isabel presented at the Birmingham Centre for Genome Biology 2025 Conference.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">CSH DNA replication meeting 2025</title><link href="/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/09/02/CSH_meeting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="CSH DNA replication meeting 2025" /><published>2025-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-09-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/09/02/CSH_meeting</id><content type="html" xml:base="/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/09/02/CSH_meeting.html"><![CDATA[<!-- excerpt start -->
<p>Angela, Anna, Conrad and Nerea attend and present at the CSH DNA replication meeting
<!-- excerpt end --></p>

<p>Another fantastic iteration of the CSHL Eukaryotic DNA replication and genome maintenance meeting. There were many facinating advances presented and a lot of interest in our work. We presented:<br />
“<em>Unbiased detection of replication initiation events in human cells using BrdU incorporation and single-molecule nanopore sequencing</em>” - Angela.<br />
“<em>Single-molecule nanopore sequencing maps replication dynamics across the fission yeast genome, including centromeres</em>” - Isabel’s work, but presented by Conrad.<br />
“<em>Single-molecule landscape of DNA replication pausing</em>” - presented by Anna as part of her collaboration with Sathish.<br />
“<em>In vivo DNA replication dynamics genome-wide at single-molecule resolution</em>” presented by Nerea as part of our collaboration with Bénédicte Desvoyes and Crisanto Gutiérrez.</p>
<figure class="figure">
  <a class="figure-image" aria-label="Nerea introducing her talk">
    <img src="/DNA-replication-group-website/images/Nerea_CSH_2025.jpg" style="
        width: 400px;
        max-height: unset;
      " alt="Nerea introducing her talk" loading="lazy" onerror="this.src = '/DNA-replication-group-website/images/fallback.svg'; this.onerror = null;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption class="figure-caption">
      Nerea introducing her talk

    </figcaption>
  
</figure>]]></content><author><name>conrad</name></author><category term="Science" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Angela, Anna, Conrad and Nerea attend and present at the CSH DNA replication meeting]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hosting Nuffield students</title><link href="/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/08/04/Nuffield-students.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hosting Nuffield students" /><published>2025-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-08-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/08/04/Nuffield-students</id><content type="html" xml:base="/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/08/04/Nuffield-students.html"><![CDATA[<!-- excerpt start -->
<p>This year we hosted three Nuffield students for a two week research placement.
<!-- excerpt end --></p>]]></content><author><name>AR</name></author><category term="Science" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This year we hosted three Nuffield students for a two week research placement.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Group day out to Sheringham</title><link href="/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/07/09/Sheringham.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Group day out to Sheringham" /><published>2025-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/07/09/Sheringham</id><content type="html" xml:base="/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/07/09/Sheringham.html"><![CDATA[<!-- excerpt start -->
<p>A whole group day trip to Sheringham to welcome Dasha.
<!-- excerpt end -->
The Nieduszynski Group donned their deerstalkers and became detectives in an interactive whodunnit that took
us across various landmarks and historical sites in Sheringham. Following the fun clues we discovered who the
murderer was just in time for lunch! After a scrumptious meal and some drinks in the The Lobster pub we
attempted a team-building spaghetti fortress exercise (which may or may not have ended in disaster) and some
Spanish card games to keep us entertained on the train home.</p>
<figure class="figure">
  <a class="figure-image" aria-label="Group picture - Case closed!">
    <img src="/DNA-replication-group-website/images/Sheringham_2025_group.png" style="
        width: 600px;
        max-height: unset;
      " alt="Group picture - Case closed!" loading="lazy" onerror="this.src = '/DNA-replication-group-website/images/fallback.svg'; this.onerror = null;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption class="figure-caption">
      Group picture - Case closed!

    </figcaption>
  
</figure>

<figure class="figure">
  <a class="figure-image" aria-label="The Leaning Tower of Pasta">
    <img src="/DNA-replication-group-website/images/pasta_tower.png" style="
        width: 400px;
        max-height: unset;
      " alt="The Leaning Tower of Pasta" loading="lazy" onerror="this.src = '/DNA-replication-group-website/images/fallback.svg'; this.onerror = null;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption class="figure-caption">
      The Leaning Tower of Pasta

    </figcaption>
  
</figure>]]></content><author><name>CC</name></author><category term="Group social" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A whole group day trip to Sheringham to welcome Dasha. The Nieduszynski Group donned their deerstalkers and became detectives in an interactive whodunnit that took us across various landmarks and historical sites in Sheringham. Following the fun clues we discovered who the murderer was just in time for lunch! After a scrumptious meal and some drinks in the The Lobster pub we attempted a team-building spaghetti fortress exercise (which may or may not have ended in disaster) and some Spanish card games to keep us entertained on the train home. Group picture - Case closed! The Leaning Tower of Pasta]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Group retreat v3</title><link href="/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/06/20/retreat-2025.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Group retreat v3" /><published>2025-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/06/20/retreat-2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/06/20/retreat-2025.html"><![CDATA[<!-- excerpt start -->
<p>Our third group retreat at the beautiful Earlham Hall on the UEA campus - joint with Julian Blow and group.
<!-- excerpt end -->
We worked up three potential future projects and enjoyed exploring the gardens and ha-ha.</p>

<figure class="figure">
  <a class="figure-image" aria-label="Earlham Hall">
    <img src="/DNA-replication-group-website/images/Earlham_hall.jpeg" style="
        width: 400px;
        max-height: unset;
      " alt="Earlham Hall" loading="lazy" onerror="this.src = '/DNA-replication-group-website/images/fallback.svg'; this.onerror = null;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption class="figure-caption">
      Earlham Hall

    </figcaption>
  
</figure>]]></content><author><name>conrad</name></author><category term="Science" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our third group retreat at the beautiful Earlham Hall on the UEA campus - joint with Julian Blow and group. We worked up three potential future projects and enjoyed exploring the gardens and ha-ha.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Norwich Scavenger Hunt</title><link href="/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/05/13/Scavenger-Hunt.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Norwich Scavenger Hunt" /><published>2025-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/05/13/Scavenger-Hunt</id><content type="html" xml:base="/DNA-replication-group-website/2025/05/13/Scavenger-Hunt.html"><![CDATA[<!-- excerpt start -->
<p>A Scavenger Hunt around Norwich.
<!-- excerpt end -->
Our team set out to explore the city with a brilliant scavenger hunt! We wandered through the 
historic Norwich lanes, discovered fun facts along the way, and wrapped up the day with some 
well-earned refreshments at BrewDog. A great mix of sunshine, laughter, and team spirit — what 
a day!</p>

<figure class="figure">
  <a class="figure-image" aria-label="Group picture">
    <img src="/DNA-replication-group-website/images/Scavenger_1.jpeg" style="
        width: 600px;
        max-height: unset;
      " alt="Group picture" loading="lazy" onerror="this.src = '/DNA-replication-group-website/images/fallback.svg'; this.onerror = null;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption class="figure-caption">
      Group picture

    </figcaption>
  
</figure>

<figure class="figure">
  <a class="figure-image" aria-label="Group picture">
    <img src="/DNA-replication-group-website/images/Scavenger_2.jpeg" style="
        width: 450px;
        max-height: unset;
      " alt="Group picture" loading="lazy" onerror="this.src = '/DNA-replication-group-website/images/fallback.svg'; this.onerror = null;" />
  </a>
  
    <figcaption class="figure-caption">
      Group picture

    </figcaption>
  
</figure>]]></content><author><name>EV</name></author><category term="Group social" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Scavenger Hunt around Norwich. Our team set out to explore the city with a brilliant scavenger hunt! We wandered through the historic Norwich lanes, discovered fun facts along the way, and wrapped up the day with some well-earned refreshments at BrewDog. A great mix of sunshine, laughter, and team spirit — what a day!]]></summary></entry></feed>